原创字幕: 人人影视
YYeTs.com
时间轴：wsr
不可能这么简单
It cannot be that simple.
你看见这些灯亮了
You saw these lights come on?
对  太阳能板放在月亮下
Yeah, when these solar panels were exposed to the moon,
或许就变成了月亮能板
Which I guess makes them lunar panels.
还记不记得在集中营里
Hey, you remember in the camp,
我们发现激光围墙
when we figured out that the laser wall
是靠飞艇供能的
was powered by the dirigible?
对  我觉得这里可能也是同一原理
Right. I think the same principle is at play here,
只不过尺度大很多
except on a much bigger scale.
我觉得艾士芬尼全部科技所需的能量
I think the Espheni are powering all their tech
都来自同一能量源
off the same power source.
-月光  -不
- Moonlight? - No.
是从月亮发出的一种能量波
A form of energy beamed from the moon.
无线电能
Wireless electricity.
特斯拉曾认为这是不可能的
Tesla thought it was possible.
艾士芬尼一定是设法完善了
The Espheni must have finally perfected it.
这也意味着艾士芬尼的能量核
And it suggests that the Espheni power core,
我们的侦察小组费了无数心思
which our Volm recon teams have found so difficult
想在地球上找到的能量核
to locate here on earth,
从来就不在地球上
was never on earth in the first place.
一直就在  我们头顶上
It was just... over our heads.
科奇斯  别对自己这么苛刻
Hey, Cochise, don't beat yourself up so badly.
我需要单独待一会儿
I need to be alone for a moment.
你觉得他们为什么把能量源建在月亮上
So, why do you think they built the power source on the moon?
从星球轨道上获取能量的唯一原因
The only reason you would beam power from orbit is if --
就是希望能为地球各处提供能量
You wanted to have a vantage point to power the entire planet.
这么说  月亮上的能量源
So, the power core on the moon
为所有集中营的所有激光围墙供能
supports every laser wall on every ghetto?
全世界的
All over the world.
所有的一切  所有迅猎兽工厂
Everything else -- every skitter factory,
我们还没想象到的所有噩梦
every nightmare that we haven't even imagined yet.
能量源为整个艾士芬尼战争机器供能
It powers the entire Espheni war machine.
这么说我们的选择不多了
Well, then I don't see that we have many options.
我们得想个办法上去
We're gonna have to figure out a way to get up there,
把那个东西炸掉
blow that son of a bitch up.
是在月亮上
It's on the moon.
-你听到了  对吧  -听到了
- You heard that part, right? - Yes!
我知道你在想什么  丹
And I know that look you're giving me, Dan.
我也知道你在笑什么
And I know that smile.
你劝疯子别跳楼的时候
I've seen it when you've tried to talk some crazy bastard
就是这个表情
from jumping off of a ledge.
那我告诉你  今天我就是那个疯子
Well, guess what. Today the crazy bastard is me.
好吧  咱们研究研究
All right. Let's, uh -- let's talk this thing through.
首先  怎么到那里
Firstly, how do we gain access to it?
-不知道  -好吧
- I don't know. - Okay.
我确定  就算咱们真找到办法
And I'm pretty sure that if we do unearth it,
-情况也不乐观  -不知道
- it's gonna be a little beat-up. - I don't know.
如果我们真找到了开关  或许能
And, hey, if we find that "on" switch, maybe we can...
不知道  不知道  不知道
I don't know. I don't know. I don't know. I don't know.
别说了
Stop saying that!
我们选择去月球
We choose to go to the moon
不是因为简单  而是因为困难
not because it's easy but because it's hard.
好吧  还开上玩笑了  你觉得好玩吗
Okay, so, this is funny? This is funny to you?
等等  等我说完
Hang on. Let me finish the speech.
因为不管你们信不信
Because, believe it or not, the first time
我第一次听到的时候  我原来也没想到
that I heard that speech, I was crazy enough to think
肯尼迪是在跟我说话
that JFK was actually talking to me.
因为这就是我们要接受的挑战
'Cause that is a challenge that we are willing to accept --
我们不愿再推迟
one that we are unwilling to postpone
我们必须胜利
and one which we intend to win.
汤姆  我们没法飞到月亮上去
Okay, Tom, we cannot fly to the moon.
我们不一定要飞上去
W-well, we wouldn't necessarily have to fly to the moon.
科奇斯
Cochise?
跟我假设一下
Just play it a little hypothetical with me.
如果能量源在月亮上
If the power core is on the moon,
那里是不是应该有艾士芬尼的某种基地
wouldn't it follow the Espheni have some kind of base up there?
应该是的
In all likelihood, yes.
既然我们知道激光飞船是遥控的
Okay, well, since we know that beamers are controlled remotely,
如果我们能找到一个方法
if we can figure out a way
把月球基地设置为目的地
to set the moon base as a destination,
咱们不就只需要搭个便车吗
wouldn't all we need to do is hitch a ride?
我都不相信我会这么说
I cannot believe I am saying this,
你这话并没有听上去那么疯狂
but it is not as crazy as it sounds.
这话比听上去疯多了
You're right. It's crazier.
只有这一个办法
I honestly don't see any other alternative.
仔细想想
I mean, think about it.
摧毁了一个迅猎兽工厂
You...close down a skitter factory,
解放了一个集中营
liberate a camp.
然后呢  我们再去下一个目标
What then -- we move on to the next one
一次次地浴血奋战拯救世界吗
and we save the world one bloodbath at a time?!
我不这么认为
I don't think so!
一次性把它们彻底击败  摧毁能量源
We got to shut them all down at the same time, at the source.
只有这个办法
That's the only way.
我们的确有个激光飞船
Well... we do have a beamer.
被埋的飞船
A buried beamer.
那就把它挖出来
So, let's unbury it.
陨落星辰
第四季 第九集
差不多了吧
Think you're about full.
整天工作  却完全没有进展
Ah, nothing like working all day and barely making a dent.
艾士芬尼炸毁了整个城
The Espheni blew up the whole town.
得花点时间清理
It's gonna take some time to clean it up.
感觉如何
How you feeling?
就像刚和迈克·泰森打了十个回合
Like I just went 10 rounds with Mike Tyson
他还用了指节铜环  刀子
and he was using brass knuckles and knives
还有一台压路机
and a steamroller.
至少他没把你耳朵咬下来
At least he didn't bite your ear off.
你起来干什么  应该好好休息
What are you doing up? You ought to be resting.
你刚进行了一次外星人刺钉移植
You just had an alien-spike transplant.
对  现在我有外星人DNA
Yeah, and now I've got alien DNA
在我的血管和肌肉里驰骋
coursing through my veins and my muscles.
疼啊
It hurts.
无法集中精力  坐不住
I can't concentrate. I can't sit still.
我得做点什么
I got to do something.
想搬一些瓦砾吗
Want to move some rubble?
想  最想干的就是这个了
Yeah, more than anything in the world.
你就像机器一样
You're like a machine.
我只是想说
Hey, I just want to say,
我知道你在这件事情上的态度
I know how you feel about all this.
我要谢谢你的支持
And I want to thank you for your support.
我不是在支持你
I'm not supporting you.
我还是觉得你疯了
I'm still thinking you're nuts.
但如果大家都听从你最新的疯点子
But as long as you've got everyone buying into your latest brand of crazy,
我不会扫大家的兴
I'm not gonna rain on their parade.
上帝知道  他们没有别的希望了
Lord knows, they don't have anything else to hope for.
所以  在他们恢复理智之前
So, until they come to their senses,
我会支持他们
I'm supporting them.
你确定就是这样吗
You sure that that's what this is about.
我不懂你在说什么
I don't know what you mean.
安  我是说亚蕾克西
Come on, Anne, I'm talking about Lexi.
听我说  发生了很多事
Listen, a lot's happened --
我们不应该相互埋怨
stuff that we shouldn't blame each other about,
我们也不应该封闭自己
stuff that we shouldn't be keeping to ourselves.
我不同意
I disagree.
我觉得有些东西就是应该
I think there are some things that are uniquely suited
好好封闭起来
to keeping to ourselves.
这个飞船不会自己钻出来
This beamer's not gonna dig itself out.
这里需要帮忙
Sure could use some more help out here.
丁甘去哪儿了
Where's Dingaan?
他和沙一起  在下面
He's down there with Shaq,
研究飞船的操控系统
trying to assess the beamer controls,
很困难  因为他们需要的那部分
which is difficult because the parts they need
还被埋着
are still buried.
他们不应该钻进那个烤箱一样的飞船里
Well, they should get their asses out of that toasty-warm beamer
应该来帮我们挖掘
and get to work helping us unbury it.
那个被烧焦的领主不会走远的
That scorched overlord isn't gonna be gone long.
早晚会发现我们还活着
Sooner or later, he's gonna figure out some of us survived,
到时它肯定会回来
and he's gonna be right back here.
我们会夜以继日地挖掘  我保证
We're gonna dig around the clock. I promise.
即使这样  也需要几周时间
Even if we do, it's gonna take us weeks.
我可能有个办法
I have a possible solution.
几英里之外  有一个隐蔽的
There is... A concealed Volm supply cache
沃尔姆补给站
several miles from here.
你在说什么  沃尔姆补给站
What are you talking about, Volm supply cache?
我们仔细研究了你们的先辈以及美国本土战争
We studied your pioneer and native American wars closely.
隐秘的供给站
Hidden supply stockpiles
对双方来说都是重要的资源
proved to be a vital resource for both sides.
这个补给站  应该存有高科技工具
This cache should contain tools with advanced technology
可用于更快速的
that could be used to break up this earth
挖掘和清理
and clear it away more quickly.
什么  沃尔姆挖掘机吗
What? Like a Volm backhoe?
震荡炮
Concussion ordnances
可以向土壤深处发射声波
capable of shooting sound waves deep into the earth,
把石头震成沙粒
turning boulders into sand,
应该能大大加速这一工程
which should expedite this process immeasurably.
为什么现在才告诉我们
Why are we just hearing about this now?
在最近一次攻击之前  艾士芬尼的队伍
Espheni forces stood between this camp and the supply cache
位于补给站和这里之间
until their recent attack.
现在它们减少了这一区域的侦查力量
They have now scaled back their reconnaissance in this area,
危险大大降低
but the risk is minimal.
好
Right.
-卡住了吗  -我能处理
- Is it stuck? - Oh, I got it.
-这里  -等我一下
- Here. - Give me a second.
-我帮你吧  -好
- No, let me help. - All right.
钢筋卡住了
It's stuck on the rebar.
好
All right.
-准备好了吗  -好了
- All right, you ready? - Yeah.
数到三  一  二  三
On 3. 1...2...3.
谁干的  他妈的...
Who did that?! Motherf...
你还好吗
Are you OK?
不好  我摔到手腕了
No! I fell on my wrist.
你没事的  好吧
All right, look, you're -- you're fine, all right?
谢谢你的同情啊
Thanks for the sympathy.
真抱歉
I'm so sorry.
她还好吗
Hey, is she okay?
她很不好  到底他妈的怎么回事
No, she's not okay! What the hell was all that about, man?
咱们去看看她有事没事
Let's go make sure she's all right.
不用了  不用了
No, no, no, don't.
让你这位长着迅猎兽脖子的女朋友离大家远点
Keep your Skitter-neck girlfriend away from everybody!
艾士芬尼想杀我们  情况已经够糟糕了
It's bad enough we got Espheni trying to kill us.
别管他
Don't worry about him.
他说得对  我就是一团糟
He's right. I'm a disaster.
我身上好痛  没法认真思考
Everything hurts. I can't think straight.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
不  我感觉就像在操作新机器
No, I feel like I'm operating new machinery,
却没人给我说明书
nobody gave me the instruction manual,
我该离大家远点
and I should just stay away from everybody.
不  我以前经历过这种事
No, I -- I've been through this before.
我可以帮助你  习惯你的感官
I can help you -- get used to your senses,
学习如何控制力量
learn how to control your strength.
是啊  如果你能那样做  那就太好了
Yeah, if you could do that, that would be great.
也许你应该接受他的提议
Maybe you ought to take him up on it.
去吧
Yeah, go on.
安
Anne.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
韦弗跟我说了沃尔姆补给站的事
Weaver told me about the Volm supply cache,
我想换个地方
and I could use some change of scenery.
你是真的生我气了吧
Wow, you really blame me, don't you?
你觉得是我让亚蕾克西改变阵营
You think I persuaded Lexi to switch sides
残忍地杀害了卢尔德吗
and murder Lourdes in cold blood?
你觉得那是我的主意吗
You think that was my idea?
不
No.
但我觉得你十分愿意尝试一切
But I think you're more than willing to try anything else,
不管是多么疯狂冒险的办法
no matter how crazy, no matter how reckless.
知道吗
And you know what?
我不想搅合进去
I do not want to get into this with you.
知道吗  也许你就是该怪我
You know what? Maybe you should blame me.
因为当本告诉我们亚蕾克西的事
Because when Ben came and told us about Lexi
说没有线索可以跟踪时
and said that there was no trail to follow,
也许我只是在寻找一个释怀的原因
maybe I was looking for a reason to move on
免得我们家的闹剧  对大家的一切
so that our family drama didn't wreak havoc on everybody
造成严重破坏
and everything for once!
但我不能跟你说
But I can't discuss that with you.
你觉得那是新鲜事吗  汤姆
You think that's something new, Tom?
你一旦得出结论
You reach a conclusion,
就默认全世界都自动同意了
and it's like the rest of the world is automatically on board!
你说得没错  我觉得并非每个问题
Guilty as charged -- I don't think that every problem
都需要民主的解决方案
has to have a democratic solution,
但现在发生的事是你很生气
but what's happening right now is that you're upset.
却不愿意跟我谈论这事
And instead of talking to me about it,
而是要封闭自己  逃避一切
you're gonna bottle that up and live in denial.
我没有逃避  汤姆
I am not living in denial, Tom.
这就是我
This -- this is me.
这就是到处奔走  努力活下来的我
This is me that's been on the road, surviving.
我花了几个月时间寻找我们女儿
This is the me who spent months searching for our daughter,
但却没有线索
and I didn't have a trail to follow.
这是两码事
That was a little different!
你不知道她变了样
You didn't know what she had become!
你只知道她是个遇上麻烦的小姑娘
For all you knew, she was just a little girl in trouble
也许她还是你唯一剩下的家人
and probably the only family you had left!
不止如此
It is more than that.
我相信  这种情况下
I believe, and what is pissing me off
让我生气的是  我不明白为什么
about this situation is I don't understand why --
-你为什么不信  -因为我信不起
- Why don't you believe? - Because I can't afford to.
你可以拥有信念  我得现实一点
You get to have faith. I have to be the realist!
我必须得权衡一切  考虑大局
I'm the one that has to weigh everything and measure everything...
即使我跟你一样为她心碎
Even in situations where my heart is breaking just as much as yours.
有些事谁也说不准
We don't know what we don't know.
也许亚蕾克西会回来  也许她没有走远
Maybe Lexi will come back. Maybe she's not too far gone.
也许  我说不好  也许阴差阳错
Maybe -- I don't know -- in some unimaginable way,
发生的一切都是必须发生的
everything that happened needed to happen
好让事情按正确的轨迹发展
so that things work out the way they're supposed to.
我不知道
I don't know.
你不是说过不能拥有信念吗
I thought you said you couldn't afford to have faith.
我没有  我不能  但我有希望
I don't. I can't. I have hope.
这是不同的  信念是你的职责
There's a difference. Faith is your department.
所以我有你  需要你
That's why I have you. That's why I need you.
你说得对
You're right.
我们继续恪尽职守吧
Let's just stick to what we do.
我来杀迅猎兽  治疗人们
I'll kill Skitters. I'll patch people up.
而你  飞向月球
You'll fly to the moon.
如果我们都活下来了  我们再...
And if we both survive, we'll just --
去弄明白其余的事
we'll just figure out the rest.
成交吗
Deal?
成交
Deal.
刚刚可真是剑拔弩张
Quite the melodrama back there.
怒气冲冲的
Stomping off, all in a huff.
你在冰箱里找东西啊
You raiding the, uh, icebox here, huh?
是啊  我找点东西来敷手腕
Yeah, I'm trying to find something for my wrist.
疼死了
It hurts like hell.
维柯丁止痛药  你不是不吃了吗
Vicodin. I thought you said you gave this stuff up.
-是啊  -怎么  掉了一片指甲
- I am. - So, what -- you chip a nail,
就旧瘾复发吗  是吗
and you've fallen off the wagon again? Is that it?
告诉你  你承诺过要保持清醒的
I'll tell you, you got one hell of a commitment
亲爱的
to sobriety, sweetheart.
你现在也许该闭嘴了
Okay, you might want to shut up right about now.
也许你应该先考虑清楚
Maybe you should think twice before you go on
再去到处进行演讲  说着以前的莎拉
giving these big public speeches about the old Sarah
和现在的莎拉  还有你戒掉了这东西
and the new Sarah and how you're off all this crap.
知道吗  我居然真的信了
'cause you know what? I actually believed you.
我真是傻逼啊
What an idiot, huh?
我刚想这么说
Took the words right out of my mouth.
马特成为了一名真正的战士
Matt's turned into quite the soldier --
跋涉几个小时  吃得很少  也不抱怨
Hiking for hours, low rations, no complaints.
你确定带上他是个好主意吗
Are you sure it was a good idea to bring him?
科奇斯说风险很低
Cochise said it was low-risk.
肯定比开垦计划要安全
It's got to be safer than that reclamation project.
在那里扭伤的脚踝和伤口
There's enough sprained ankles and cuts
一辈子都好不完
to last a lifetime there.
什么味道
What's that smell?
我觉得是氯气
I think it's chlorine.
这片地区有致命的毒气
There are lethal patches of toxicity throughout this area.
马修  你打开行李袋
Matthew, if you'll open your duffel bag.
好
Uh, sure.
你们都得戴上
You'll all need to put one of these on.
真好
Oh, lovely.
你究竟为何
Any particular reason
要在毒废料场藏东西
you decided to hide your stash in a toxic dump?
毒气能有效防止食腐动物入侵
The toxicity is an effective deterrent to scavengers.
我们沃尔姆可以呼吸氯气
We Volm can breathe chlorine.
补给站在这个水箱下面四英尺的地方
The cache is buried 4 feet below this cistern.
你应该有办法进去吧
I assume you have a way to access it.
马特
Matt!
米拉
Mira?
你没事吧
Are you okay?
坚持住
Hang in there.
她会没事的吧
She gonna be okay?
我能呼吸了
I can breathe.
你在这里待着  离那边远点就没事
You'll be all right over here, away from that crap.
你怎么会在这里
What are you doing out here?
我终于出来了
I finally got out.
我做到了  马特  我逃出来了
I did it, Matt. I escaped.
马特跟我们说了你的很多事
Matt told us a lot about you.
看来你俩在集中营里互相照顾
Sounds like you guys looked out for each other at that camp.
马特救了我的命
Matt kept me alive.
我真害怕我永远也逃不出来
I was afraid I'd never get out of there.
你怎么逃出来的
Yeah, how did you?
我是照你的吩咐做的
I did just what you told me to.
我假装和他们相处融洽  直到他们让我毕业
I pretended to go along with them until they let me graduate.
感觉怎么样
What was that like?
太古怪了
Oh, man, it was so weird.
队长肯特教了我很多
Team leader Kent taught me all these things,
比如怎么找难民  逃亡者和军人
like how to find refugees, escapees, militias,
如何让他们信任你  如何发警报
how to get them to trust you, how to raise the alarm.
等等  你说发警报是什么意思
Wait. W-what does that mean, raise the alarm?
如果我们发现外人  就该吹响
There was this whistle that we were supposed to blow
一个口哨
if we found any outsiders.
他们特别想让我们找到家庭成员
They especially wanted us to track down family members --
找到相信我们的人
People that would trust us.
口哨会叫来激光飞船  进行袭击
The whistle calls a beamer strike.
然后迅猎兽会来吗
And then the Skitters come?
不  青年集中营的队长们会来
No, team leaders from the youth camp I was held in.
抓住这些异议分子  然后带回艾士芬尼
They capture the dissidents and take them back to the Espheni.
你的口哨呢
Where's your whistle?
我一出来就把它丢进了河里
I-I threw it in the river as soon as I left.
我才不想要那些东西
I didn't want any part of that thing.
真高兴你找到了我
I'm so glad you found me.
真走运
Pretty lucky.
我躲在树林里
I was hiding in the woods,
看着道路  等着会带我和他们一起走的人
watching the road for someone who would take me with them.
然后你们来了  我以为我看见了马特
And then you all came along, and I thought I saw Matt,
但我猜那只是我痴心妄想
but I figured it was just wishful thinking.
所以你刚好碰到我们吗
So, you just happened to come across us?
在沃尔姆补给站
At a Volm weapons cache.
我完全不知道
Yeah, I had no idea.
拜托  你们必须得相信我
Please, you have to believe me.
米拉  这样做是为了大家的安全  站起来
Mira, what I have to do is keep everybody safe. Stand up.
爸爸  你要干什么
Dad, what are you doing?
爸爸  她是我的朋友
Dad, she's my friend!
我知道  希望那是真的  马特
I know. I hope that's true, Matt,
但我不会冒险
but I'm not gonna take any chances.
不能把她扔在这里啊
Can't just leave her here!
我们不会把她扔在这里
We're not gonna leave her here.
她要在这里歇着  直到我们完成过来的任务
She's gonna rest here while we do what we came to do.
这些是管道还是触手
Are these tubes or tentacles?
艾士芬尼科技模仿的是肌肉骨骼系统
Espheni technology mimics a musculoskeletal system.
线是连起来的  它们的动作是协调的
The cords are connected, and their movement is coordinated.
所以  如果我拉动这根线
So, if I pull on... this cord...
有东西动了  我听到了
Something moved. I heard something.
试试另外一根
Try another.
是从那边传来的
That came from over here.
这两条绳子是相连的
These two are connected.
我们得进到墙里面
We have to get inside these walls
标注线之间的联系
and map the connections between the cords,
得出一个判断结论
Create a diagnostic
表明哪根线控制什么动作
showing which cords control which movements.
只有挖出激光飞船  我们才能做到
Which we can't get to until the beamer has been unearthed.
你真的觉得震荡炮
You really think those concussion ordnances
能完成任务吗
can do the trick?
我就当你默认了
Okay, I'll take that as a yes.
为什么跟着我
Why are you following me?!
因为没人能离开我
Because nobody walks away from me!
是吗  以为自己很了不起啊  珀普
Oh, god. Think much of yourself, Pope?
关你什么事  你想让我痛苦吗
What do you care?! Do you want me to be in pain?!
-是吗  -没错
- Is that it?! - Right now?! yes!
-这里以前是个博物馆  -知道吗
- Think this used to be a museum. - You know what?
让我一个人待着
Just -- just leave me alone.
闭嘴啊
Shut up, already!
什么
What?
不是说你
No, not you.
我能听见珀普和莎拉的对话
I can hear Pope and Sarah's conversation,
珀普很凶
and Pope's being a jerk.
莎拉的声音好尖
Sarah's voice is a really shrill voice.
你会习惯的
You'll get used to that.
你总能听到所有人的对话吗
Do you listen to everyone's conversations all the time?
现在不会  你会慢慢学会怎么无视的
No, not anymore. You, um... you learn to tune things out.
那你就走好了
You know what? Get lost!
天哪  我希望这些声音消失
God, I want them out of my head!
转移一下注意力  这边
Focus on something else. Come here.
没事  来吧  从这儿跳下去很容易的
It's okay. Come on. We could easily make this jump.
不要  我不想跳
No, no, uh, I don't want to.
很简单的  来吧  我教你
It's a piece of cake. Come on. I'll show you.
本  你别管我了行吗
Ben, just leave me alone, all right?
走开
Back off.
没事的  我知道感觉会有点怪
It's okay. I -- I know it feels weird.
不是怪  是被侵入的感觉
No, it doesn't feel weird. It feels invasive.
就好像我身体内有东西在爬  在侵占我
Like something's crawling inside of me, taking me over,
但我却毫无办法
and there's nothing I can do about it.
玛吉  我保证  有天
Maggie, I promise, one day,
你会爱上你的新能力
you're gonna love your new powers.
你会比以前更强更霸气
You're gonna be stronger and more badass than ever.
这话真中听
That sounds pretty sweet.
是啊  你相信我吗
It is. Trust me?
3  2  1
3...2...1.
你没事吧
You okay?
我的手好痛
My hands are killing me.
我不能放开你
Well, I can't untie you.
我理解
I understand.
我好想你
I missed you so much.
我也是
I missed you, too.
真的很痛吗
Do they really hurt?
我觉得手要被勒断了
The rope is cutting into me.
他绑的太紧了
He tied it too tight.
我知道我一定会后悔的
I know I'm gonna regret this.
别傻了
Don't be silly.
谢谢  马特  真的
Thank you, Matt... really.
过来
Here.
知道吗  你走后我在改教营过的很艰难
You know, it was really hard in the camp after you left.
我是想让你和我们一起走的  但
W-well, I wanted to make you come with us, but...
我知道  但你知道吗
I know. But you know what?
其实我很高兴我没有那么做
I'm actually glad I didn't.
我学到了很多
I learned so much.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
我们把一切都想错了
We were wrong about everything.
你真的应该留下的
You really should have stayed.
不要
No!
不  说真的
No, seriously,
我从没感觉这么棒过
that's the most amazing I've ever felt.
真不理解你居然不经常跳楼
I don't know how you're not jumping off of roofs all the time.
换做是我只要有机会我就会上去
I'd be up there every chance I got.
其实我刚开始  也像你这样
Well, uh... I kind of was, in the beginning.
我会在夜里偷偷跑出去
I mean, I'd sneak out at night
从高处跳下或者奔跑
and jump or run faster
跑得前所未有的快
than I've ever run before in my life,
就好像在比赛中一样
almost like I was in a race,
只是  参赛者只有我一个
Except, I guess, it was only a race with myself.
后来我发现  我会吓到别人
Eventually, I realized I was freaking people out,
我就只在必要情况下才显露
so I brought it down to a need-to-jump basis, you know?
我想我会经常跳的
I think I'm gonna need to jump a lot.
我们可以一起跳
We can jump together.
只要提前给大家说一声
We'll just warn everybody first.
就这么定了
Deal.
你感觉怎么样
How are you feeling?
感觉很棒  太赞了
Like, great, amazing.
我是说移植后的疼痛
I mean, your pain from the transplant.
还感觉的到吗
Is it still there?
没有  不痛了
No. It's gone.
我突然发现的
I'm just realizing it's gone.
刺钉逐渐感觉到它们
The spikes are starting to understand
是你的一部分了
that they're part of you.
等等  你说的好像它们自己有思想一样
Wait. You make it seem like they've got a mind of their own.
它们有的
They do.
它不仅是肉体的力量
This isn't just physical strength.
是种外星生物在试图融入你的人类基因
There's an alien life-form fusing with your human DNA.
它是  想要控制你的
It -- it wants to control all of you.
它想
It wants?
是的  它有感觉  有愿望
Yes, it has feelings, desires
比你经历过的都要强得多
stronger than anything you've ever felt.
所以  我可能会非常非常生气
So, I'm gonna be really, really mad sometimes?
或者非常非常饿
And really, really hungry.
天哪
Oh, no.
而且会好奇  害怕
And curious and afraid
或者  有时候
and... sometimes really, really...
深深坠入爱河
in love.
当你快乐时  你会处于狂喜之中
And... when you're happy, you're ecstatic.
有时候我会想起入侵之前的生活
Sometimes I think about life before the invasion.
我们在波士顿  坐在我屋里  看着书
We were back in Boston, sitting in my room, reading a book.
我觉得好快乐  都没法收起脸上的笑容
And I feel so happy, I can't stop smiling.
但接着
But then...
怎么
What?
我会想起我妈妈  想起我失去了她
I think about my mom -- losing my mom.
积极和消极的感受都会被放大
It works both ways.
我能感到你的悲伤  好像是自己的一样
I can feel your sadness like... like it's mine.
这倒是第一次见
That's new.
我想我们只能习惯这点了
I guess we're just gonna have to get used to that, too.
从现在开始  你要多加小心
You have to be careful, from now on, that...
在你学会掌控你的力量前
it's easy to get overwhelmed and lose yourself until...
你会很容易崩溃  会迷失自我
you learn to control your power.
好吧
All right.
我要怎么做
How do I do that?
多用用它
Use it.
准备好找点乐子了吗
Ready to have some fun?
-漂亮  -武器
- Good! - Weapons.
我们可以带走
We'll take them.
真棒
Outstanding.
要小心这个
Now, be very careful with this.
这是什么
What is it?
次空间通讯器
Subspace communicator.
精确调整过  可以接收所有艾士芬尼的通讯
Highly tuned to all manner of Espheni communications.
它可以帮助我们穿过敌人的防火墙
This will enhance our ability to cut through enemy firewalls
和数光年外的沃尔姆援军的联络
to contact Volm reinforcements light-years away.
弄坏了你要赔哦
You break it, you buy it.
那震荡炮呢
What about the compression ordnance?
那不是我们来的目的吗
Wasn't that the main reason for our joyride here?
爸  爸
Dad! Dad!
我不是说让你别去接近她吗
I thought I told you to leave her back there!
我不该放开她的  但她说手很痛
I shouldn't have untied her! But her hands hurt.
她把这个藏在了鞋子里  而且吹响了
She had this in her shoe, and she blew it!
你有什么要解释的吗
You want to explain yourself?!
不  我宽恕你  汤姆·梅森
No. Let me forgive you, Tom Mason.
天哪  她是他们的人了
Oh, god, she's on their side.
我们得撤离这里
We need to get the hell out of here.
大家找掩护  这边
Everybody take cover! This way!
米拉  米拉
Mira! Mira!
我还没找到震荡炮呢
I haven't located the concussion ordnance yet.
快走
Let's go!
有什么要和我说的吗
You got something to say to me?
没什么
Not particularly, no.
没有  真的吗  一句也没有吗
No? Really, not -- not a word to say?
你真打算站在这儿
Are you honestly gonna stand there,
跟我因为我没说的话辩论吗
debating me on what I haven't even said yet?
难以置信
Unbelievable.
你知道什么才是难以置信吗
No, you know what's unbelievable?
是你根本不用去想
What's unbelievable is that you never have to wonder
一个人究竟是什么样
what a person's really like --
我是说他的内在
I mean really like, on the inside --
因为你和一个人接触的越多
'cause the more you hang out with them,
就会越了解他  而他表现出的
the more you get to know them, when they reveal themselves,
也更贴近真实的自己
they'll show you exactly who they are.
让让行吗
Do you mind?
我已经理解了你伟大的自我展现
Just so I understand this thunderous revelation of yours,
你觉得我跟你说我是什么样的人了
what exactly do you think that I told you I was?
你是个瘾君子
You're an addict.
说明你很懦弱  而且是个骗子
That means you're weak... and you're a liar.
我没资格评论你
Now, I'm not the one to judge,
但你也不是我认识的第一个瘾君子了
but... this isn't my first rodeo.
我了解你们  而且我不打算成为那个
I know addicts, and I am not gonna be the one
被你利用  被你欺骗
that you use and you lie to
然后被你抛弃的人
and then move along.
所以  再见吧
So bye-bye.
我怎么利用你了
In what way did I use you?
告诉我啊  我怎么利用你了
Tell me! In what way did I use you?!
遇见你之前我过的很好
I was fine before I met you!
从来没有被迅猎兽袭击过
I-I'd never been attacked by skitters!
也没有杀过任何东西
I had never killed anything!
但我一直和你并肩作战
But I fought with you, side by side,
为了你冒着生命危险
risking my life for you!
你就看见我手里拿了一瓶药
And you see me with one pill bottle in my hand,
你就认定我是骗子和瘾君子吗
and your go-to response is that I am a liar and a user?!
你知道我怎么想吗  我想是你胆怯了
You know what I think? I think you're afraid.
你害怕我们可能的将来
I think you're afraid of what we might be.
别给我费劲分析了  我没兴趣
Spare me the analysis. I'm not interested.
显而易见
Obviously not.
你知道这瓶里是什么吗
You know what's in this bottle?
维柯丁[止痛药]
Vicodin!
阿司匹林
Aspirin.
一切都乱套的时候标签弄错了
The labels got mixed up when everything went to crap.
用心看里面  才知道装的是什么
You do actually have to look to know what's inside.
马特  马特
Matt! Matt!
-你见到马特了吗  -我想他去那边了
- Have you seen Matt? - I think he went that way!
是青年营的领队
It's the team leaders from the youth camp!
冲啊  乔尔  冲啊
Go, Joe, go! Go!
米拉  救救我
Mira... help me.
太晚了
It's too late for that.
他跑不了了  抓住他
This one isn't going anywhere. Get him!
米拉  救救我
Mira, help me.
科奇斯
Cochise!
这个眩晕弹应该能拖住他们几小时
That stun should hold them for a few hours.
带着这个什么也看不见
I can't see in this thing!
这里的空气没问题  你可以摘下面罩了
The air's okay here! You can take it off.
我没子弹了  你还好吗
I'm empty. You all right?
我也没了  我还好
I got nothing left. Yeah, I'm fine.
我们得找个更好的掩护
We need to find better cover than this.
安
Anne!
你没事吧
You all right?
没事
I'm okay!
待在原地不要动
Stay where you are!
汤姆·梅森  我是肯特·马修领队
Tom Mason, this is team leader Kent Matthew.
我们抓住了你儿子  马特
We have your son, Matt!
他晕了过去
He is subdued!
现在给他打了镇定剂
He's being collected right now!
我们不想伤害你  汤姆
We don't want to hurt you, Tom!
我们是来带你去安全的地方的
We're here to take you to safety!
战争结束了
The war is over.
我们的艾士芬尼兄弟姐妹想要
Our Espheni brothers want to
欢迎我们进入他们的社会
welcome us into their society!
请你和我们走吧  汤姆
Please, come with us, Tom.
你没子弹了  汤姆
You're out of bullets, Tom.
现在只是时间问题了
Now it's just a matter of time!
出来吧  我不会伤害你
Come out! I won't attack!
停战
Truce!
那些烟可是有毒的  汤姆
Those fumes are toxic, Tom!
那个集装箱随时都可能爆炸
That container could explode at any moment!
你最好还是出来吧
You better come out!
等一下
Hey, wait!
安
Anne?
等一下
Hey, wait!
你怎么能对自己人做出这种事情
How could you do this to your own people?
只有接受艾士芬尼兄弟们我们才能进步
Progress is made when we embrace our Espheni brothers.
我不是叛徒  我是新的爱国者
I'm not a traitor. I'm a new patriot.
汤姆
Tom...
我把我母亲  交给了它们
I gave them...my mother.
快到了  就快到了
Here you are. Here you are.
他在这
Here he is.
老爸
Dad.
你决定留下了吗
You decided to stay?
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
我以为你跟莎拉一起走了
I figured you were going with Sarah.
她几个小时前来过
She came by a few hours ago,
拿走了一把步枪和几天的口粮
Picked up a rifle, a couple days' rations.
怎么会呢
How?
她说她知道附近有座农场
She said she knew of a nearby farm
那里可能会有些食物
where there might be some food.
我以为你会跟她一起去呢
I just assumed you were going with her.
好了  展示一下你的本领吧
Okay, let's see what you can do.
正中目标
Bull's-eye.
继续  那边还有很多
Keep going. Plenty more where that came from.
你现在觉得我怎么样
How do you like me now?
我太喜欢你了
I like you too much.
对不起
I'm so sorry.
我不应该那么做
I shouldn't have done that.
我很高兴你做了  不过...
I'm glad you did, but...
-哈尔  -是的
- Hal. - Yeah.
天哪  我疯了吗  我...
Oh, my God, am I going crazy? I...
自从我醒来之后有了刺钉
Since I woke up with the spikes,
我就感觉  被你吸引住了
I feel like... I'm drawn to you.
你以前没有这种感觉吗
Yeah, and you didn't before?
没有  我爱  我爱哈尔
No, I love -- I love hal.
这个  这种感觉不一样
This... this feels different.
天哪  这种感觉太强烈了
God, this is so intense.
我...
I...
我现在太想吻你了
I really want to kiss you right now.
不要
Don't.
我知道  我知道
I know. I know.
我知道
I know.
天哪
Oh, God.
看来我们暂时  不会遇到阻碍了
Looks like we're in the clear... for the time being.
我应该向大家道歉
I owe you all an apology.
我误导了你们  给你们带来了不必要的危险
I misled you, put you at unnecessary risk,
而且我们甚至没有拿到我们要找的东西
and we did not even retrieve the essential item we came for.
我们回去之后
We'll just have to dig a little harder
努力点把飞船挖出来就是了  科奇斯
when we get back, Cochise.
你怎么样
How are you doing?
很疼
It hurts...
就像一千多根针在扎我
like a thousand needles sticking into me.
我想也是
Bet it does.
很抱歉我在米拉的事上犯傻了
Sorry about being such an idiot about Mira.
你才13岁
You're 13.
早恋也不容易
puppy love is not easy,
特别是在生死攸关的时候
especially when it's life-and-death.
这不是早恋  老爸
It's not puppy love, dad.
我想让你忘了她  但我觉得你未必能做到
I'd tell you to forget about her, but I doubt you could.
听上去可能有些奇怪
Strange as it sounds,
但那应该记住你对她的感觉
you should try to remember the feeling you had for her.
这种感觉很重要
The feeling is important.
为什么
Why?
因为你在生活中  很难遇到一个
'Cause it's pretty rare in life when you meet somebody
彼此都很在意对方的人
who cares about you as much as you do about them.
玛吉怎么样了
Hey, how did things go with Maggie?
还行  挺好
Fine. Good.
你的那些  刺钉
Those-- those spikes of yours --
它们能帮你很快愈合  对吧
they help you heal quickly, right?
-是的  -很好
- Yeah. - Good.
你应该帮玛吉适应她的刺钉
You were supposed to help Maggie adjust to her spikes.
并不意味着可以对我女朋友有想法
doesn't mean it's open season on my girlfriend.
-哈尔  我绝不会  -本
- Hal, I would never -- - You know what, Ben?
省省吧  我都看见了
Just save it, okay? Because I saw you.
我明白
And, look, I get it.
她很漂亮  很出众  但她是我的人
She's gorgeous. She's amazing. But she's mine.
不好意思
I'm sorry.
我没看见她脖子上有你的链子
I didn't see your leash on her.
离她远点
Just stay away from her.
大家好
Hey, everybody.
我还有点担心你们呢
I was starting to worry about you guys.
我们遇到了点麻烦  不过有惊无险
We ran into a little trouble. We made it out.
老爸
Dad!
一切都顺利吗
Everything go okay?
你的脸怎么了
What happened to your face?
没事
Nothing.
好吧
Okay.
丁甘
Dingaan.
那个外星引擎修得怎么样了
How goes the alien small-engine repair?
不怎么样
Not great.
这些碎石使得我们无法靠近控制设施
The rubble prevents us getting to the necessary controls.
你们找没找到那个
Were you able to bring back that tool
挖掘激光飞船的工具
to help us raise the Beamer?
没有  我们遇到了埋伏
No, we got ambushed.
那个补给站被摧毁了
The cache was destroyed.
又回到了原点  不过这也不是第一次了
Back to square one, but it wouldn't be the first time.
睡觉前把这些武器
Let's get these weapons and supplies
和物资收拾起来
stowed before we get some shut-eye.
我找到了这个
I did find this.
按理说  这个可以召唤激光飞船
Supposedly, this can call Beamers.
我不知道是靠特定的音色还是频率
I don't know if it's a tone or a frequency.
你看看能研究出什么来  小心一点
See what you can do with it. Be careful.
千万别吹
Do not blow that.
我去找沙研究一下  你来吗
I'll take it to Shaq right away. Coming?
好
Yeah.
现在
Now...
你们两个小子有什么要跟我说的吗
anything you boys need to tell me?
没有
No.
好吧
Okay.
你听听我记的对不对
So, let me see if I remember this correctly.
我们被包围了
We were surrounded.
情况很糟糕  只有一个办法能出去
Situation sucked, and only one way out,
有一个人需要牺牲自己  我
And that's for one of us to be dead -- me.
有一个人需要聪明的活下去  你
One has to be smart and stay alive -- you.
这是我们交战时的基本准则
Those are the basic rules of engagement.
我在"山区碉堡社区大学"里教过这一课
Used to teach a course on it at Bunker Hill Community College.
饶了我吧
Give me a break.
可是你没做出聪明人该做的事
But instead of doing the smart thing, you...
如果我没记错的话  你手无寸铁地跑了出去
if my memory serves, ran out without a weapon,
没有任何计划  还大喊了一句
without a plan, and yelled --
什么来着  "等一下"
what was it, again? -- "Hey, wait"?
我当时不知道该说什么
I didn't know what else to say.
"等一下"就是你的神勇计划
"Hey, wait"? that was your big master kamikaze plan?
"等一下  看那里
"Hey, wait, look over here!
等一下  别杀他  杀我"
Hey, wait, don't shoot him! Shoot me!"
你以为你要死了
I thought you were going to die.
我知道
I know.
如果你中枪的话  我可能也会做
I probably would have done the same dumbass thing
这种蠢事
if you were the one getting shot.
但是我在想
But I've been thinking.
子弹没打中你可能是有原因的
Maybe there's a reason the bullets missed you.
你说"如果我们这次能活下去
When you said to me, "If we survive this,
我们会解决好其它事的"
we'll figure out the rest,"
这让我听了很难受
That was very hard for me to hear,
因为我不知道"其它事"是指什么
because I don't really know what "the rest" means,
但是  我后来意识到我才不关心呢
but... then I realized I don't really care.
无论这段时间是长是短
Whether it's a long time or a short time,
我都想跟你在一起
I just want to spend it with you...
如果你愿意的话
if you'll have me.
-这听上去好像是...  -就是
- That sounds like... - It is.
天哪
My God.
我知道这不容易
I'm not saying it's gonna be easy.
但你愿意嫁给我吗
But will you marry me?
愿意
Yes.
等一下  我们怎么知道这么做是不是对的
Wait. How do we know we're doing the right thing?
不知道  我们不知道
We don't. We don't.
但我还抱有希望
But I have hope.
愿意
Yes.
我愿意
我承诺在交战时永远支持你
I promise to always have your back in a firefight,
我也承诺尽量不被杀死
and I promise to try not to get killed.
我的承诺与你一样
I promise to do the same.
安  你是否愿意与他一起
So, Anne... do you take this man...
无论情况好坏
for better, for worse...
富贵贫贱
for richer, for poorer...
疾病健康
in sickness or in health...
直到死亡将你们分开
till death do you part?
是的  我愿意
Yeah. I do.
我也愿意
I do, too.
据我所知  你现在可以亲吻新娘了
Well, as far as I'm concerned, you may kiss the bride.
汤姆·梅森  我必须要跟你谈谈
Tom Mason... I must speak with you.
看在上帝的份上  我们在举行婚礼啊
For God's sake, we're having a wedding here!
等我跟汤姆·梅森谈完
You may resume your ritual
激光飞船的事  你们的仪式可以继续进行
after I speak to Tom Mason about the Beamer.
激光飞船更重要
The Beamer is important.
恭喜你们
Congratulations.
你为什么要打断我们
So, why the hell did you interrupt?!
我一直在分解你带回来的艾士芬尼的哨子
I have been deconstructing the Espheni whistle you brought back.
你说对了
You are correct.
它可以跟激光飞船直接通信
It communicates directly with the Beamer...
发动引擎
engaging the engine.
好吧  它还能干什么
Okay, what else can it do?
它能得到月球的归航信标吗
Can it access the homing beacon on the Moon?
需要一个不同的信号
A different signal is required
来指引激光飞船飞向某个特定地方  不过
to direct the Beamer to a certain location... but --
不过这是个开始
But he's saying it's one hell of a start,
你这个疯子
You crazy son of a bitch.
我分离出了哨子的归航振幅
I was able to isolate the homing amplitude of the whistle.
是超声频率  人类听不到
It is an ultrasonic frequency that humans can't hear
而且人类的技术也不知道该找什么
and human tech wouldn't know to look for.
我用这个通信器捕捉到了这个信号
I've captured the signal within this communicator.
好的  这对我们有什么帮助
Okay. How does it help us?
退后
Stand back!
Back!
我想这就是答案
I guess that's how.
我们要去月球了
We choose to go to the moon.